Finding Aid for Office of the Associate Vice President for Facilities and Operations records (University of Michigan) records, 1925-2006
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Office of the Associate Vice President for Facilities and Operations (University of Michigan) records 1925-2006, 1989-1999
University of Michigan. Office of the Associate Vice President for Facilities and Operations.
17 linear feet
2014161 Bimu 2
Records of unit responsible for facilities management and regulatory compliance at the University of Michigan. Includes minutes, correspondence, reports, proposals, and archived websites.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donated by the Office of the Associate Vice President for Facilities and Operations (Donor no. 10706 ), in January, 2012.
Periodic additions to the records expected.
University records are public records and once fully processed are generally open to research use. Records that contain personally identifiable information will be restricted in order to protect individual privacy. Certain administrative records are restricted in accordance with university policy as outlined below. The restriction of university records is subject to compliance with applicable laws, including the Freedom of Information Act.
The Associate Vice President for Facilities and Operations record group includes restricted material in the following categories:
Executive Officers Records -- Boxes 1-17
Executive records (including University records generated by Executive Officers, Deans, Directors and their support offices) are restricted for a period of twenty years from their date of accession by the Bentley Historical Library. The restriction is subject to applicable law, most notably the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA).
The University of Michigan Office of the Associate Vice President for Facilities and Operations reports to the Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer is responsible for managing the university's physical properties, including academic, research, and clinical facilities, as well as environmental stewardship and regulatory compliance. The unit was previously named the Office of the Associate Vice President for Business Operations. In 1970, it had the following units under it: Plant Extension, Plant Manager, Personnel Director, Purchasing Director, Safety Director, and Utilities Manager. In 1999, the name was changed to Office of the Associate Vice President for Facilities and Operations with Henry Baier serving as Associate Vice President. As of 2014, subordinate departments include Architecture, Engineering, and Construction; Parking and Transportation Services; Plant Operations; Occupational Safety and Environmental Health; and Office of Campus Sustainability.
The records of the Office of the Associate Vice President for Facilities and Operations are contained in two series, Topical and Archived Website.
Subjects:
Angell Hall (University of Michigan); Crisler Arena (University of Michigan); Gordon Hall (University of Michigan); Hill Auditorium (University of Michigan); Inglis House (University of Michigan); Michigan Stadium (Ann Arbor, Mich.); North Campus (University of Michigan); University of Michigan--Administration.; University of Michigan--Buildings.; University of Michigan. Health System.; University of Michigan. Hospitals.; University of Michigan. Office of the Associate Vice President for Facilities and Operations.; University of Michigan--Security measures.; University of Michigan--Student housing.; University of Michigan. Transportation Services.; Venturi Scott Brown and Associates.
Genre Terms:
Websites.
- Topical
  The Topical series documents the management of university facilities and property, primarily during the 1990s. It is arranged as it arrived upon accession, essentially alphabetically by facility, topic, or unit. Records in this series include committee minutes, correspondence, aerial photographs, architectural drawings, financial reports, design and construction proposals, budget proposals, contracts, risk management assessments, inspection and test results, etc.
  - AEC: Plant Extension Committee 1989-1999 (Box 1)
    [ER RESTRICTED until July 1, 2032 ]
  - Altarum 1987-1997 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Association 1992-1999 (Box 1)
  - Americans with Disabilities Act 1997-1999 (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor
    - (City of)
      - General 1997-1999 (Box 1)
      - Easements 1994-1996 (Box 1)
      - Payments to the City 1998-1999 (Box 1)
    - Township 1994-1999 (Box 1)
  - Arbor Heights 1938-1998 (Box 1)
  - Arbor Lakes 1994-1999 (Box 1)
  - Arboretum 1971-1999 (Box 1)
  - Art and Architecture Building 1984-1999 (Box 1)
  - Art on Campus 1989-1999 (Box 1)
  - Asbestos 1999 (Box 1)
  - Athletics
    - General 1993-1999 (Box 1)
    - Women's Crew Facility 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - Bagnoud Building 1972-1994 (Box 1)
  - Banners 1999 (Box 1)
  - Bentley Historical Library 1972-1999 (Box 1)
  - Bicycles 1999 (Box 1)
  - Big Ten Association 1999 (Box 1)
  - Biological Station 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - Bonisteel Interdisciplinary Research Building 1999 (Box 1)
  - Botanical Gardens (Matthaei)
    - General 1998-1999 (Box 1)
    - Fleming Creek 1999 (Box 1)
  - Boyer Building 1997 (Box 1)
  - Briarwood Properties 1995 (Box 1)
  - Buhl Building 1999 (Box 1)
  - Buhr Building 1977-1999 (Box 1)
  - Burton Tower 1999 (Box 1)
  - Business Administration
    - General 1992-1996 (Box 1)
    - Davidson Institute Lease 1993-1996 (Box 1)
  - Business and Finance
    - Business Plan 1999 (Box 1)
    - CFO Correspondence 1998-1999 (Box 1)
    - Data Systems 1998-1999 (Box 1)
    - Diversity Committee 1991-1999 (Box 1)
    - Financial Affairs Committee/Senate Advisory Committee 1997-1999 (Box 1)
    - Meritorious Awards 1999 (Box 1)
  - Camp Knight 1998-1999 (Box 2)
  - Campus Plan 1999 (Box 2)
  - Campus Safety Services Building 1987-1996 (Box 2)
  - Cancer Center 1988-1999 (Box 2)
  - Canham Natatorium 1984-1997 (Box 2)
  - Central Campus Moves 1998-1999 (Box 2)
  - Central Power Plant 1991-1999 (Box 2)
  - CFO Funding Transfers 1998-1999 (Box 2)
  - Chemistry Building 1990 (Box 2)
  - Chrysler Center 1990-1999 (Box 2)
  - Classrooms 1999 (Box 2)
  - Clements Library 1987-1999 (Box 2)
  - Commencement 1996 (Box 2)
  - Martha Cook Building 1979-1998 (Box 2)
  - Crisler Arena 1972-1997 (Box 2)
  - Dana Building: Phase II Renovation Project 1996-1999 (Box 2)
  - Dearborn Campus 1997-1999 (Box 2)
  - Delegations of Authority 1998-1999 (Box 2)
  - Dennison Building 1999 (Box 2)
  - Dental School 1992-1999 (Box 2)
  - Detroit Observatory 1971-1994 (Box 2)
  - Development 1999 (Box 2)
  - Diag 1992-1998 (Box 2)
  - Duderstadt Center 1988-1999 (Box 2)
  - East Ann Arbor Health and Geriatrics Center 1999 (Box 2)
  - Education (School of) 1998-1999 (Box 2)
  - Electrical Engineering and Computer Science Building 1999 (Box 2)
  - Energy Conservation 1999 (Box 2)
  - Engineering (College of)
    - General 1994-1999 (Box 2)
    - Capital Planning 1999 (Box 2)
  - Finance and Capital Projects Committee 1988-1999 (Box 2)
  - Facilities and Operations
    - Correspondence 1998-1999 (Box 2)
    - Organizational Charts 1999 (Box 2)
    - Training 1998-2000 (Box 2)
  - Financial Analysis 1999 (Box 2)
  - Fleming Building: Space 1998-1999 (Box 2)
  - Flint Campus
    - General 1990-1999 (Box 2)
    - Northbank Center 1998 (Box 2)
  - Ford Library 1979-1995 (Box 2)
  - Forest Hills Cemetery 1993-1996 (Box 2)
  - Freedom of Information Act: Requests 1999 (Box 2)
  - Fresh Air Camp 1925-1999 (Box 2)
  - Frieze Building 1979-2007 (Box 3)
  - Fuller Road/Bridge 1963-1994, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - E. S. George Reserve 1997-1999 (Box 3)
  - Gerstacker Building 1973-1999 (Box 3)
  - Good Letters 1990-1999 (Box 3)
  - Gordon Hall
    - Sale Specific 2004-2006 (Box 3)
    - Chronology 2003-2005 (Box 3)
    - History 1950-2004 (Box 3)
    - Historic District 1997-2001 (Box 3)
    - Misc 2000-2006 (Box 3)
    - Free Press FOIA 2005 (Box 3)
    - Media Clips 2001-2006 (Box 3)
    - Rental Properties 1951-1971 (Box 3)
    - Letters of Support 2001-2005 (Box 3)
  - Government Relations 1996-1999 (Box 3)
  - Graffiti 1986-1999 (Box 3)
  - Grand Haven Aquatic Research Center 1997 (Box 3)
  - Handicapped (Box 4)
    - General 1992-1997 (Box 4)
    - Parking 1977-1997 (Box 4)
  - Hatcher Graduate Library 1976-1999 (Box 4)
  - Health Administration Press 1984-1989 (Box 4)
  - Health Service Building 1999 (Box 4)
  - Hill Auditorium 1989-1999, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Historic Preservation 1977-1996 (Box 4)
  - Housing
    - General 1992-1999, 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Residence Halls 1980-1998 (Box 4)
  - Human Resources and Affirmative Action 1996-1999 (Box 4)
  - Indirect Costs 1991-1994 (Box 4)
  - Information (School of) 1997-1999 (Box 4)
  - Information Technology Division 1986-1999 (Box 4)
  - Ingalls Mall 1977-1992 (Box 4)
  - Inglis House 1968-1998, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Institute for Continuing Legal Education 1984-1998 (Box 5)
  - Institute for Social Research 1970-1999 (Box 5)
  - Kellogg Eye Center 1979-1999 (Box 5)
  - Kitt Peak 1974-1996 (Box 5)
  - Kraus Building 1987-1998 (Box 5)
  - Kresge Medical Research Buildings 1963-1995 (Box 5)
  - Landscaping 1971-1999 (Box 5)
  - Lane Hall 1997-1999 (Box 5)
  - Law School 1970-1998, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Lay Automotive Laboratory 1982-1996 (Box 5)
  - Leased Property
    - General 1992-1999 (Box 5)
    - Victor Office Center Lansing 1992-1995 (Box 5)
    - Wolverine Tower Tenant Leases 1993-1997 (Box 5)
  - Libraries 1989-1993 (Box 5)
  - Life Sciences Institute 1998-1999 (Box 6)
  - Lighting on Campus 1990-1998 (Box 6)
  - Literature, Science, and the Arts
    - Building 1999 (Box 6)
    - (College of) 1983-1998 (Box 6)
  - Little (C. C.) Science Building 1979-1999 (Box 6)
  - Lloyd Memorial Laboratories 1986-1989 (Box 6)
  - Lorch Hall 1972-1999 (Box 6)
  - Lurie Engineering 1993-1998 (Box 6)
  - 109 E. Madison 1993-1998 (Box 6)
  - Maintenance (Deferred) 1993-1998 (Box 6)
  - Mason Hall 1987-1998 (Box 6)
  - Maxey Flats 1987-1995 (Box 6)
  - McKay Tower 1982-1999 (Box 6)
  - Medical School Campus 1983-1998 (Box 6)
  - Medical Science
    - Incinerator 1983-1998 (Box 6)
    - Research Building 1
      - General 1982-1993 (Box 6)
      - 1992 P32 Spill and NRC Action, 1992-1993 (Box 6)
    - Research Building 2 1984-1992 (Box 6)
    - Research Building 3 1981-1991 (Box 6)
    - Unit I and II 1984-1998 (Box 6)
  - Mental Health Research Institute 1984-1995 (Box 6)
  - Michigan Gateway 1992 (Box 7)
  - Michigan Information Technology Network 1997 (Box 7)
  - Michigan League 1977-1995 (Box 7)
  - Michigan Memorial Phoenix Laboratory 1994-1998 (Box 7)
  - Michigan Radio 1978-1998 (Box 7)
  - Michigan Stadium 1968-1998 (Box 7)
  - Michigan Union 1984-1998 (Box 7)
  - Modern Languages Building 1973-1984 (Box 7)
  - Mott Children's Hospital 1964-1992 (Box 7)
  - Museums 1962-1997 (Box 7)
  - Music, School of 1980-1995 (Box 7)
  - NACUBO 1998 (Box 7)
  - Naval Architecture and Marine Engineering Building 1970-1996 (Box 7)
  - Neuroscience Building 1970-2001 (Box 7)
  - North Campus
    - General 1984-1998 (Box 7)
    - Computing Center 1990-1998 (Box 7)
    - Incinerator 1975-1998 (Box 7)
    - Transfer Facility 1993-1997 (Box 7)
  - North Campus Administrative Complex 1982-1998, 3 folders (Box 8)
  - North Hall/ROTC 1975-1997 (Box 8)
  - North University Building 1982-2002 (Box 8)
  - North University Plaza 1994 (Box 8)
  - School of Nursing Building 1979-1997 (Box 8)
  - Occupational Safety and Environmental Health
    - General 1992-1998 (Box 8)
    - DNR Consent Judgment 1995-1997 (Box 8)
    - Environmental Impairment Liability 1996 (Box 8)
    - Landfill 3 1992-1995 (Box 8)
    - Low-level Radioactive Waste 1993-1996 (Box 8)
  - Organizational Charts 1995-1997 (Box 8)
  - Oxford Housing 1962-1998 (Box 8)
  - Parke-Davis 1982-1998 (Box 9)
  - Parking and Transportation Services
    - Transportation Services 1991-1998 (Box 9)
    - Parking 1991-1998, 3 folders (Box 9)
    - Parking Complaints 1995-1998 (Box 9)
    - Merger 1998 (Box 9)
  - Parking Lots
    - General 1982-1998 (Box 9)
    - Buffalo Parking Lot 1998 (Box 9)
    - VA Parking Agreement 1992-1993 (Box 9)
  - Parking Structures
    - General 1986-1999 (Box 9)
    - Forest Avenue Parking Structure 1998-1999 (Box 9)
    - Palmer Drive Parking Structure 1996-1997 (Box 9)
  - Pedestrian Connections 1990-1995 (Box 9)
  - Perry Building 1985-1999 (Box 9)
  - Pest Control 1976-1998 (Box 9)
  - Pharmacy (College of) 1982-1989 (Box 9)
  - Pierpont Commons 1988-1999 (Box 9)
  - Planner's Office 1989-1998 (Box 9)
  - Plant Operations (Box 10)
    - General 1993-1999 (Box 10)
    - Building Services 1998-1999 (Box 10)
    - Grounds and Waste Management 1994-1999 (Box 10)
  - Pound House 1968-1997 (Box 10)
  - Power Center 1965-1999 (Box 10)
  - Presidents Council, State Universities of Michigan 1992-1999 (Box 10)
  - President's Office 1989-1999 (Box 10)
  - President's Residence
    - General 1987-1997 (Box 10)
    - Furnishings 1990-1998 (Box 10)
  - Privatization 1985-2000 (Box 10)
  - Property
    - Acquisitions and Sales 1975-1999, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Easements 1989-1999, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Misc 1981-1998, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - 142 East Hoover 1995-1996 (Box 11)
    - 1912 Geddes (Nu Sigma Nu), 1998-2005 (Box 11)
    - 712 Oakland (Oakland Annex) 2001-2004 (Box 11)
    - 733 South State Street 1995-1996 (Box 11)
    - 777 Eisenhower 1990-1996 (Box 11)
    - Ann Arbor Railroad 1975-1996 (Box 11)
    - Ann Arbor Technology Park 1982-1999, 3 folders (Box 11)
    - Base Lake Property 1965-1998 (Box 11)
    - Bass Lake Property 1996-2001 (Box 11)
    - Chesterfield Twp, Macomb County Property 1992-1993 (Box 11)
    - Consolidated Rail (Conrail) 1981-1994 (Box 11)
    - Newcomb Tract 1971-1993 (Box 11)
    - Shady Trails Camp 1977-1998 (Box 11)
    - Sheridan Properties (Huron HS Parking Lot) 1963-1990 (Box 11)
    - Stegemen Properties 1981-1998 (Box 11)
    - Tuomy House 1967-1982 (Box 11)
    - Wall Street Properties 1990-1999 (Box 11)
    - Zina Pitcher Place (Bank of America) 1998-1999 (Box 11)
  - Provost's Office 1996-1998 (Box 11)
  - Public Health (School of) 1966-1999 (Box 11)
  - Purchasing 1995-2001 (Box 11)
  - Rackham Building 1972-1999, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Radiation Control (Box 12)
    - Radiation Policy Committee Membership 1988-2000 (Box 12)
    - Radiation Policy Committee 1986-2000 (Box 12)
    - Radiation Safety Service 1991-2000 (Box 12)
  - Radrick Farms 1979-1997 (Box 12)
  - Randall Laboratory 1999-2000 (Box 12)
  - Recreational Sports
    - General 1991-1995 (Box 12)
    - Central Campus Recreation Building 1986-1999 (Box 12)
    - Coliseum 1972-1977 (Box 12)
    - Recreational Fields 1969-1998 (Box 12)
  - Recycling 1989-1997 (Box 12)
  - Regents Office
    - General 1988-1997 (Box 12)
    - Regents' Ordinance 1990-1999, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Regents' Plaza 1980-1996 (Box 12)
  - Regulations 1993-1998 (Box 12)
  - Research (Office of VP) 1987-1999 (Box 12)
  - Revelli Band Rehearsal Hall 1972-1989 (Box 12)
  - Risk Management 1985-1999 (Box 12)
  - Ronald McDonald House 1983-1996, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Saginaw Forest 1974-1997 (Box 12)
  - Schembechler Hall 1989-1992 (Box 13)
  - Security
    - Campus Safety and Security Advisory Committee 1985-1999, 4 folders (Box 13)
    - Domestic Violence 1992-1993 (Box 13)
    - DPS COPS Grants 1995-1999 (Box 13)
    - Fire Safety 1989-1996 (Box 13)
    - Football 1991-1997 (Box 13)
    - Hash Bash 1996-1999 (Box 13)
    - Naked Mile 1997-1999 (Box 13)
    - Parking Enforcement Agreement 1992-1995 (Box 13)
    - Police Mutual Aid Agreements 1992-1995 (Box 13)
    - Police Oversight Committee 1992-1998 (Box 13)
    - Police Services Contracts 1990-1998 (Box 13)
    - Public Safety 1995-1999, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Radios and Alarm Systems 1987-1997 (Box 13)
    - Task Force on Campus Safety and Security 1990-1997 (Box 13)
    - Violence in the Workplace 1995 (Box 13)
  - Senate Advisory Committee on University Affairs 1986-1999 (Box 13)
  - Shapiro Library 1975-1994 (Box 13)
  - Shepherd Women's Gymnastics Center 1999 (Box 13)
  - Sidewalks 1965-1996 (Box 13)
  - Simpson Memorial Institute 1997-1998 (Box 13)
  - Sims-Varner 1989-1993 (Box 13)
  - Social Work (School of) Building 1989-1999, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Space 1992-1999 (Box 14)
  - Space Research Laboratory 1985-1996 (Box 14)
  - Standard Practice Guide 1992-1999 (Box 14)
  - State of Michigan
    - Budget Requests 1995-1998 (Box 14)
    - Capital Outlay Requests 1993-1999 (Box 14)
    - Public Acts 1990-1997 (Box 14)
    - State-funded Projects 1992-1999 (Box 14)
    - Use and Finance Statements/JCOS Reporting 1996-1999 (Box 14)
  - Stearns Building 1982-1998 (Box 14)
  - Stinchfield Woods 1948-1999 (Box 14)
  - Streets and Roadways 1967-1999, 5 folders (Box 14)
  - Student Activities Building 1970-1999 (Box 14)
  - Student Affairs 1991-1998 (Box 15)
  - Student Publications Building 1980-1999 (Box 15)
  - Sustainability 1999 (Box 15)
  - Tally Hall 1998-2000 (Box 15)
  - Tank Registration 1993-2000 (Box 15)
  - Tappan Hall 1981-1993 (Box 15)
  - Taubman Medical Library 1977-1999 (Box 15)
  - Telecommunications 1993-1996 (Box 15)
  - Tisch Tennis Center 1990-1997 (Box 15)
  - Towsley Children's House 1983-1998 (Box 15)
  - Treasurer's Office 1989-1999 (Box 15)
  - Trotter House 1972-1996 (Box 15)
  - Tunnels 1993-1999 (Box 15)
  - Turner Gerontology 1973-1990 (Box 15)
  - Ulrich's 1999 (Box 15)
  - University Budget and Finance Group 1998-1999 (Box 15)
  - Unions 1990-1999 (Box 15)
  - Unit for Lab Animal Medicine 1980-1994 (Box 15)
  - University Condo Association 1990-1999 (Box 15)
  - University Golf Course 1990-1997 (Box 15)
  - University of Michigan Health System
    - General 1988-1999 (Box 15)
    - Ann Arbor Airport Hangar 1992-1994 (Box 15)
    - Child Care Center 1988-1991 (Box 15)
    - East Medical Campus 1994-1997 (Box 15)
    - Maternal and Child Health Center 1970-1987 (Box 15)
    - Medical Center Transportation Planning 1984-1993 (Box 15)
    - Parking 1982-1994, 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Parkview Hospital 1978-1996 (Box 16)
  - University of Michigan Transportation Research Institute 1996-1999 (Box 16)
  - University Seal 1995 (Box 16)
  - Utilities
    - General 1992-1999 (Box 16)
    - Detroit Edison 1964-1999 (Box 16)
    - MichCon 1989-1993 (Box 16)
    - Rates 1998-1999 (Box 16)
  - Victor Vaughan Building 1980-1991 (Box 16)
  - Vending 1988-1993 (Box 16)
  - Venturi Scott Brown and Associates
    - Andropogon 1997-1999 (Box 16)
    - BRW Medical Center Report 1999-2000 (Box 16)
    - Central Campus Moves 1998-2001 (Box 16)
    - Central Campus Programming 1998-1999 (Box 16)
    - Contracts 1998-2002 (Box 16)
    - Health System Invoices 2001-2002 (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous 1997-2004 (Box 17)
    - Parking and Transportation 1998-1999 (Box 17)
    - University of Michigan Health System 1998-2002, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Veterans Administration Hospital 1986-1995 (Box 17)
  - Walgreen Drama Center 1998-1999 (Box 17)
  - Washtenaw Development Council 1992-1997 (Box 17)
  - Weill Hall 1998-1999 (Box 17)
  - Wolverine Tower 1990-1999, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Year 2000, 1998-1999 (Box 17)
  - Yost Ice Arena 1994-1995 (Box 17)
- Archived Website
  The Archived Website series includes captures of the Facilities and Operations website and contains information about the unit's structure and responsibilities, guidelines for using facilities, and links to the websites of its subordinate departments. The series includes content captured by the Internet Archive starting in 2005. Since 2010, this archived website has been captured on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at http://webarchives.cdlib.org/a/universityofmichigan/.
  - 2005-2008
    (These versions were preserved by the Internet Archive and are made available through its Wayback Machine. The Bentley Historical Library is not involved in the collection or maintenance of this material.)
  - 2008-[ONGOING]
  - 2010-[ONGOING]